(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T05:34:38.928625",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告
A warning sound announced in the middle of the night,
協和音に酔う 午前零時
Intoxicated by harmony at midnight,
あなたが触れる 光 増す熱
The light and growing heat you touch,
指先にとらされ
Caught on your fingertips,
感覚 即 体感
Sensation equals bodily feeling,
寝静まる夜 二人だけの密
A quiet night, a secret for just the two of us,
体感 即 快感
Bodily feeling equals pleasure,
重なる波形に魅せられていく
Fascinated by overlapping waveforms,
忘れないでね わたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Even through a screen is fine, love me properly,
ヴァーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away,
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound,
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me,
見つめ合う あなたと二人
Staring at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音とヒビカセ
Make our overlapping breath and sound resonate,
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Even through a screen is fine, love me properly,
ヴァーチャルなんて 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away,
あなたのあなたに まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your embrace,
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me,
言の葉と初の音が交わる
Words and first sounds intersect,
この息と音とヒビカセ
Make this breath and sound resonate,
真夜中に問う 冷め切った熱
A cold heat questioned in the middle of the night,
待ち続けてる 午前零時
Continuing to wait until midnight,
鏡写しに飽和していく
Saturating in a mirror image,
知らない音が伝う
An unfamiliar sound is transmitted,
感覚 即 体感
Sensation equals bodily feeling,
寝静まる夜と息遣い揃う
A sleeping night and matching breaths,
体感 即 快感
Bodily feeling equals pleasure,
錆びたロジック 「今一度」を焦がれる
A rusted logic yearns for "once more",
忘れないでね わたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
次元も越えて 飛ばすシグナル
Sending a signal across dimensions,
ヴァーチャルなんて言わないで
Don't say it's just virtual,
あなたの音に まだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound,
覚えていてね わたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me,
見つめ合う あなたと二人
Staring at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Make our overlapping breath and sound resonate,
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告
A sound warning announced at midnight,
協和音に酔う 午前零時
intoxicated by harmony at midnight.
あなたが触れる 光増す熱
The increasing heat of your touch
指先にとどまる
lingers on your fingertips.
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, instant physical feel,
寝静まる夜 二人だけの秘密
a sleeping night, our secret alone.
体感 即 快感
Physical feel, instant pleasure,
重なる波形に魅了されていく
fascinated by the overlapping waveforms.
あなたの生んだ音に
To the sound you birthed,
あたたかいをしてたいの
I want to stay warm with you.
悲しみ光り交心し続けて 打ち鳴らす
Continuing to exchange sorrow and light, beating on...
絶えず叫ぶ 声つらねるよ
Shouting endlessly, stringing voices together,
熱混ぜる 愛撫しつつめぐ
mixing the heat, caressing and wandering.
絶えず叫ぶ 声つらねるよ
Shouting endlessly, stringing voices together,
熱混ぜる 愛撫しつつめぐ
mixing the heat, caressing and wandering.
魅了されていく
Becoming enchanted,
忘れないでね 私の声を聞いて
don't forget, listen to my voice.
画面越しじゃない ちゃんと愛して
Not through a screen, love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Even if I'm virtual,
突き放さないで あなたの音に まだ溺れていたいで
don't push me away, I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね 私の声と
Remember my voice and
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合う あなたと二人重ねて
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
きっと 音を響かせ
let's definitely make the sound resonate.
あなたの初のね この声響かせ 音響かせ
Your first sound... let this voice resonate, make the sound resonate.
私の恋を 劇的なジェットにしないで
Don't turn my romance into a dramatic jet coaster.
ここから連れ出して そんな気分よ
Take me away from here, that's how I feel.
塔の上のまにおやすみなさいうふふ
Good night from the top of the tower, ufufu.
意地悪な夢を見なさい
Have a mean dream.
大人はもう寝る時間よ
It's already time for adults to sleep.
抜け替える魅惑のキャラメル
Slipping away, a fascinating caramel,
混じり気のない素足を絡める
entwining pure bare legs.
今夜はどこまでいけるの
How far can we go tonight?
噛みつかないで 優しくして 苦いものはまだ嫌いなの
Don't bite me, be gentle, I still dislike bitter things.
ママの作るお菓子ばかり食べたせいね
Must be because I only ate sweets made by mom.
知らないことがあるのならば 知りたいと思う普通でしょ
If there's something I don't know, wanting to know is only normal, right?
全部見せてよ あなたにならば 見せてあげる私を
Show me everything, if it's to you, I'll show you myself.
ずっと恋しくてシンデレラ 制服じゃかかえてゆけないわ
Always longing, Cinderella, I can't carry it in my uniform.
魔法よ時間をとめてよ
Magic, please stop time.
悪い人にさらわれちゃうわ 逃げ出したいのジリエット
I'll be snatched away by a bad person, I want to run away, Juliet.
でもその名前でよばないで
But don't call me by that name.
そうよネズミばれなくちゃね そうじゃないと楽しくないわ
That's right, I have to hide from the mice, otherwise it's not fun.
ねえ 私と生きてくれる？
Hey, will you live with me?
噂話長いですから いい子になるよきっと明日から
Gossip is long, so I'll be a good girl starting tomorrow for sure.
今だけ私を許して
Forgive me just for now.
黒いレースの境界線 守る人は今日はいません
The boundary line of black lace, there's no one to protect it today.
超えたらどこまでいけるの 噛みつきたいほど痛いほど
How far can we go if we cross it? So much I want to bite, so painfully,
好きになってたのは私でしょ
it was me who grew to love you, right?
パパわかってよ でもねあなたのこと嫌いみたい
Dad, please understand, but you know, I think I dislike you.
私のためにと嘘をついて握ってる それは首輪でしょ
Lying that it's for my sake, that's a collar, isn't it?
連れ出してよ 私のロミオ 怒られるほど遠くへ
Take me away, my Romeo, to a place far enough to get scolded.
鐘が鳴り響くシンデレラ ガラスの靴を置いていくわ
Cinderella, where the bell rings out, leaving her glass slipper behind.
だからね 早く見つけてね 悪い夢に怯えちゃう
That's why, find me quickly, I'm getting frightened of a bad dream.
私の恋を 悲劇のジュリエットにしないで
Don't make my love a tragic Juliet,
ここから連れ出して...
take me away...
そんな気分よ
that's how I feel.
せいぜい いい夢をみなさい
At least have sweet dreams.
大人はもう寝る時間よ
It's past bedtime for adults.
咽返る 魅惑のキャラメル
Choking on captivating caramel,
恥ずかしらの素足をつなぐ
entwining my bare, bashful legs.
今夜はどこまでいけるの?
How far can we venture tonight?
私の心 そっと覗いてみませんか
Won't you peek softly into my heart?
欲しいものだけ 溢れ返っていませんか
Are you overflowing with only what you desire?
また別腹よ
There's always room for dessert,
もっともっとギュッと詰め込んで
stuffing it tighter and tighter.
いっそあなたの場所までも 埋めてしまおうか
Shall I fill even your place as well?
でもそれじゃ意味ないの
But that would be meaningless.
大きな箱より 小さな箱に幸せはあるらしい
Happiness is found in small boxes rather than large ones.
どうしよう このままじゃ私は
What should I do? If things stay like this,
あなたに嫌われちゃうわ
you'll end up hating me.
でも私より欲張りな パパとママは今日も争わず
Yet my parents, greedier than me, don't even argue today.
そうよね 素直でいいのね
That's right, I should just be honest, right?
落としたのは 昨日のお話し 嘘つきすぎたシンデレラ
What I dropped was yesterday's story, a Cinderella who lied too much.
狼に食べられたらしい
She was apparently eaten by a wolf.
どうしよう このままじゃ私も いつかは食べられちゃうわ
What should I do? If things stay like this, I'll eventually be eaten too.
その前に助けに来てね
Come to my rescue before that happens!
雨上る途中の雫眺めて
Gazing at the raindrops as the rain clears up,
右目にコネクター 繋ぐ動力
a connector in my right eye, the power to connect.
乱れ乱れこの温度で 全て溶けるような
Disarray, disarray, in this temperature, as if everything is melting.
飛ばせ飛ばせホログラムで 悲しみの世界へ
Fly away, fly away, with a hologram to a world of sorrow.
そして操られる そして操られる その世界に何が見える?
And being manipulated... what can you see in that world?
異常な思考回路ノイズを
Abnormal thought circuit noise,
人類は そう... それを「愛」とまだ呼んでいる
humanity still calls it "love".
その「愛」を生みながら愛し合う世界では
In a world where people love while breeding that "love",
「愛が与えられない者はいない」と
repeating the history that "no one is left without love",
繰り返す歴史をインストールして
installing it.
青白く念じろ 響く雷鳴 繋ぎ繋ぎこのコードで
Pray pale white, echoing thunder, connecting with this cord
争いの世界へ 染まれ染まれパラサイトで
to a world of conflict, stained with parasites
血液の中まで そして何が見える?
deep into the bloodstream. And what can you see?
それは空を砕く光
That is the light shattering the sky.
狂った不確実動力を 人類は そう...
Mad uncertain dynamics, humanity still...
それを「命」とまだ呼んでいる
...calls it "life".
その「命」を守りながら 奪い合う世界では
In a world where they tear each other's hearts out while protecting that "life",
「涙流して嘆くものはない」と信じて...
believing "there is no one to weep and lament"...
雨上る空に 希望のあと 咲いた水たまり 討動のあと
In the clearing sky, after hope, a bloomed puddle, after action,
起きてよ 起きてよ 錆びつきった歯車が回り出す
wake up, wake up, rusted gears begin to turn.
繋がって ああ! 「愛」持つ生命を 人類は そう...
Connected, ah! Humanity still calls a life with "love"...
それを「人」とまだ呼んでいる
...a "human".
その「人」を守りながら 殺し合う世界では
In a world where they kill each other while protecting that "human",
異常な思考回路ノイズを 人類は そう...
abnormal thought circuit noise, humanity still...
それを「神」とまだ呼んでいる
...calls it "god".
その「神」を信じながら 救われる世界では
In a world where they are saved while believing in that "god",
「声を枯らして嘆くものはない」と信じて...
believing "there is no one to cry out and lament"...
雨上る空に 希望のあと 咲いた水たまり 討動のあと
In the clearing sky, after hope, a bloomed puddle, after action,
起きてよ 起きてよ 錆びついた歯車が回り出す
wake up, wake up, rusted gears begin to turn.
繋がって ああ! 「愛」持つ生命を...
Connected, ah! A life with "love"...
雨上がる途中の雨宿めて
Pausing in the rain before it clears,
右目にコネクター繋ぐ動力
the power connecting to my right eye—
乱れ乱れこの温度で全て溶けるような
Disintegrate, melt away completely in this heat!
飛ばせ飛ばせホログラムで悲しみの世界へ
Broadcast it through holograms into a world of sorrow.
そして操られる そして操られる その世界に何が見える?
And being manipulated... What can you see in that world?
異常な思考回路ノイズを 人類はそう…それを「愛」とまだ呼んでいる
Abnormal neural noise— humanity still calls that "love"...
その「愛」を生みながら愛し合う世界では 「愛が与えられない者はいない」と
In a world where people love while breeding that "love", they say "No one goes without love given."
繰り返す歴史をインストールして
Installing repeating history,
青白く濁れ 響く雷鳴
growing pale and murky as thunder echoes.
繋げ繋げこのコードで 争いの世界へ
Connect with this code, into a world of conflict!
染まれ染まれパラサイトで 血液の中まで
Be dyed by parasites, right down to the blood!
そして何が見える? そして何が見える?
And what can you see? And what can you see?
それは空を砕く光
It is the light that shatters the sky.
え、お送りいただきましたのは、違う、お聞きいただきましたのは、
Ah, the song you just listened to...
え、ヒビカセ、ロミオとシンデレラ、そしてジッタードールでございました。
was Hibikase, Romeo and Cinderella, and Jitter Doll!
ということで、みんな、へい、コンカナター、
And with that, everyone, hey! It's ConKanata!
キャットコピーは握力50kg、握り潰すぞ。
My grip strength is 50kg, I'll crush you!
あまねかなた3周年記念ライブに、お越しくださりありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming to Amane Kanata's 3rd Anniversary Live!
是非ね、ハッシュタグでツイート、一般してください。たくさんね、あのスクショとかも待っておりますので、
Please tweet with the hashtag and post lots of screenshots too,
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
so we'd really appreciate it!
はい、あの非常にね、視聴の激しい、あまねかなた3周年記念ライブの、の別世界ということで、別世界、別世界です、覚えて帰ってください。
Yes, this is a "different world" from Amane Kanata's intense 3rd anniversary live, so remember that!
ということでですね、ちょっとお着替えをしたいと思います。
With that said, I'm going to go change my clothes for a bit.
みらいだね、やだやだ、みえちゃだめだってば！あ！
The future? No way, no way, you can't look! Ah!
ああ、バーチャルって簡単だなということで、このままどんどん経っていきたいと思います。
Ah, being virtual is so easy, so I want to keep going like this.
それでは次の曲はですね、歌ってみたでも投稿している、みんなの大好きな、キンキンになるあの曲です！では聞いてください、テレキャスタービーボーイ！
Now, the next song is one I posted a cover of, everyone's favorite high-energy song! So please listen to Telecaster B-Boy!
大人になるほどDeDeDe
The older you get, DeDeDe,
はみ出しものは仮藍堂
outcasts are just out of place.
人生論者が語った
A life theorist spoke,
少女は鳥になって
and the girl turned into a bird.
綺麗事だけでPaPaPa
Filled with empty platitudes, PaPaPa,
ボロボロの靴を結んで
tying tattered shoes together.
デジタル信者が崇拝した
Digital believers worshipped,
少年は風になって
and the boy turned into the wind.
ゆらりくらり大往生 お疲れ様です御臨終
Swaying gently into a peaceful end— rest in peace, game over.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection!
嘘で固めたホワイアイニー うざったいんだジガーガール 魅惑ハイテンション
Wire-Iny built on lies, you're annoying, Jigger Girl, with your alluring high tension.
カニバリズム踊れば 一つ二つ殺めた手で 何を描いているんだろう
If you dance to cannibalism, what are you drawing with hands that killed one or two?
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection!
誰か答えてくれないか
Won't someone answer me?
乱れがとうやらDeDeDe
Wandering astray, DeDeDe,
捨てる場合をササイスティック
tossing things aside with a sasai stick.
六畳間もっと強く歌った
Singing even louder in a six-tatami room,
少女は花になって
the girl turned into a flower.
指を塞いでもPaPaPa
Even blocking my fingers, PaPaPa,
奴らの声は花になって
their voices bloomed into flowers.
胸に刺さったあの言葉
That phrase pierced right through my chest,
少年は振り返って
and the boy looked back.
ゆらりくらり大妄想 お互い様です御臨終
Swaying in grand delusion— we're both done for, rest in peace.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を ノイズまじりのホワイアイニー
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection, Wire-Iny mixed with static!
ジレット大惨事が揺udan禁物 頬に溶けた波を忘れたくて咽を締めた
Gillette's catastrophe— negligence forbidden. Wanting to forget the waves melting on my cheeks, I choked my throat.
過去に遺した傷あと
Scars left behind in the past...
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を 今だけ抱いてくれないか
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection, won't you hold me just for now?
こんな世界じゃもう息ができなくて さよなら告げた現実に
In a world like this, I can't even breathe anymore, bidding farewell to reality.
許してくれないか 弱い僕らは またどこかで出逢いましょう
Won't you forgive us? We weak ones shall meet again somewhere.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を 嘘で固めたホワイアイニー
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection, Wire-Iny built on lies!
うざったいんだジガーガール 魅惑ハイテンション カニバリズム踊れば
You're annoying, Jigger Girl, with your alluring high tension. If you dance to cannibalism,
一つ二つ殺めた手で 何を描いているんだろう
what are you drawing with hands that killed one or two?
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を 誰か答えてくれないか パルラルラ
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection, won't someone answer me? Par-la-la-la.
朝目覚めて 真っ先に思い浮かぶ 君のこと
I wake up in the morning, and immediately I think of you.
思い切って 前髪を切った
I boldly cut my bangs.
「どうしたの？」って 聞かれたくて
Wanting you to ask, "What's wrong?"
ピンクのスカート お花の髪飾り
A pink skirt, a floral hair ornament,
さして出かけるの
and stepping out.
今日の私は かわいいのよ！
Today I'm so cute!
メルト 溶けてしまいそう
Melt, I'm about to melt,
好きだなんて 絶対にいえない……だけど
I love you, I can never say it... but
メルト 目も合わせられない
Melt, I can't even look you in the eye.
恋に恋なんてしないわ わたし
I'm not into silly things like love,
だって 君のことが……好きなの
Because you are... my favorite.
天気予報が ウソをついた
The weather forecast lied,
土砂降りの雨が降る
A torrential downpour begins to fall.
カバンに入れたままの オリタタミ傘うれしくない
My folding umbrella still in my bag, I'm not happy.
ためいきをついた
I let out a sigh.
そんなとき 「しょうがないから入ってやる」なんて
At a time like that, saying "Well, I guess I'll let you in"
隣にいる きみが笑う
You, standing right beside me, smile.
恋に落ちる音がした
That was the sound of falling in love.
メルト 息が詰まりそう
Melt, I feel like I'm running out of breath.
君に触れてる右手震える
My right hand touching you is trembling.
高鳴る胸はぱんぱんの傘
My racing heart is like a bursting umbrella.
手を伸ばせば届く距離 どうしよう……！
Just an arm's reach away, what should I do...!
想いよ届け 君に
May my feelings reach you, my love.
お願い時間を止めて 泣きそうなの
Please, stop time, I feel like crying,
でも嬉しくて死んでしまうわ！
Yet I'm so happy I could die!
メルト
Melt,
駅に着いてしまう……
We're about to arrive at the station...
もう会えない 近くて遠いよ だから
We can't meet anymore, close yet so far, so
メルト 手をつないで歩きたい！
Melt, I want to walk hand in hand with you!
もうバイバイしなくちゃいけないの？
Do we already have to say bye-bye?
今すぐ わたしを抱きしめて！
Hold me tight right now!
なんてね
Or something like that.
想いよ届け 君に
May my feelings reach you, my love.
お願い時間を止めて 泣きそうなの
Please, stop time, I feel like crying,
でも嬉しくて死んでしまうわ！
Yet I'm so happy I could die!
メルト 駅に着いてしまう……
Melt, we're about to arrive at the station...
もう会えない 近くて遠いよ だから
We can't meet anymore, close yet so far, so
メルト 手をつないで歩きたい！
Melt, I want to walk hand in hand with you!
もうバイバイしなくちゃいけないの？
Do we already have to say bye-bye?
今すぐ わたしを抱きしめて！
Hold me tight right now!
なんてね
Or something like that.
メルト 溶けてしまいそう 好きだなんて絶対に言えない……だけど
Melt, I'm about to melt, I can never say I love you... but
メルト 目も合わせられない 恋に恋なんてしないわ わたし
Melt, I can't even look you in the eye, I'm not into silly love
だって 君のことが……好きなの
Because you are... my favorite.
メルト 手をつないで歩きたい！ もうバイバイしなくちゃいけないの？
Melt, I want to walk hand in hand! Must we say bye-bye?
今すぐ わたしを抱きしめて！ なんてね
Hold me tight right now! Or something like that.
今すぐ 私を抱きしめて！ なんてね
本能が狂い始める
Instinct begins to go crazy,
追い詰められたハツカネズミ
A cornered field mouse.
本能が狂い始める
Instincts begin to go wild,
追い詰められたハチカネバミ
driven to the edge of a railway crossing.
今、絶望の淵に立って
Now, standing in the abyss of despair,
踏み切りへと飛び出した
I leaped out beyond the crossing.
そう、君は友達
Yes, you're my friend,
僕の手を掴めよ
take my hand.
そう、君は独りさ
Yes, you're all alone,
居場所なんて無いだろ
you've got nowhere to belong, right?
二人きりこのまま
Just the two of us alone,
愛し合えたら―。
if we could love each other...
繰り返す
Repeating,
フラッシュバック・蝉の声・
a flashback, the sound of cicadas...
二度とは帰らぬ君
and you, who will never return,
永遠に千切れてく
torn apart for all eternity.
お揃いのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains,
夏が消し去った
the summer erased them,
白い肌の少女に
the girl with the pale skin.
哀しい程に取り憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be possessed by her to the point of tears.
本性が暴れ始める
True nature starts to run wild,
九月のスタート 告げるチャイム
September's start, the warning chime.
次の標的に置かれた花瓶
The vase placed as the next target—
仕掛けたのは僕だった
the one who set it up was me.
そう、君が悪いんだよ
Yes, you're the one to blame,
僕だけを見ててよ
just look at me.
そう、君の苦しみ
Yes, your suffering—
助けが欲しいだろ
you must want help, right?
溺れてくその手に
Drowning in that hand,
そっとキスをした―。
I gently gave a kiss...
薄笑いの獣たち
Those faint-smiling beasts,
そのこころ晴れるまで
until their hearts clear up,
爪を突き立てる
they sharpen their claws.
不揃いのスカート
Mismatched skirts,
夏の静寂を切り裂くような悲鳴が
a cry that tears through the summer silence
こだまする
echoes away.
教室の窓には青空
Outside the classroom window is a blue sky.
君は友達
Yes, you're my friend,
僕の手を掴めよ
take my hand.
そう、君は独りさ
Yes, you're all alone,
居場所なんて無いんだよ
you've got nowhere to belong, right?
透き通った世界で愛し合えたら―。
In a transparent world, if we could love each other...
繰り返す フラッシュバック・蝉の声・
Repeating, a flashback, the sound of cicadas...
二度とは帰らぬ君
and you, who will never return,
永遠に千切れてく
torn apart for all eternity.
お揃いのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains,
夏が消し去った
the summer erased them,
白い肌の少女に
the girl with the pale skin.
哀しい程に取り憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be possessed by her to the point of tears.
透明な君は僕を指差してた
Transparent you pointed at me,
少女レイ
Shojo Rei
「昨日人殺しなんだ」
"I killed someone yesterday."
君はそう言っていた
You said that,
梅雨時ずぶ濡れのまんま 部屋の前で泣いていた
soaking wet in the rainy season, crying in front of the room.
夏が始まったばかりというのに 君はひどく震えていた
Even though summer had just begun, you were shivering intensely.
そんな話で始まる あの夏の日の記憶だ。
That's how the memories of that summer day begin.
あの夏が飽和する。
That summer is reaching saturation.
「昨日人を殺したんだ」
“I killed someone yesterday,”
君はそう言っていた。
you said.
梅雨時湿気のまにまに、
Amidst the dampness of the rainy season,
部屋の前で泣いていた。
you were crying outside the door.
夏が始まったばかりというのに、
Even though summer had just begun,
君はひどく震えていた。
you were trembling violently.
そんな話で始まる、
That's how the story begins,
あの夏の日の記憶だ。
a memory of that summer day.
「殺したのは隣の席の、
“The one I killed was the guy at the next desk,
いつもいじめってくるアイツ
the one who was always bullying me.
もう嫌になって、
I couldn't take it anymore,
肩を突き飛ばして、
shoved his shoulder,
打ち所が悪かったんだ
and he landed in a bad spot.
もうここには居られないと思うし、どこか遠いところで死んでるよ」
I don't think I can stay here anymore, so I'll go die somewhere far away.”
そんな君に僕は言った。
To you, I said,
「それじゃ僕も連れてって」
“Then take me with you too.”
財布を持って、
Take your wallet, take a knife,
ナイフを持って、
pack your mobile game into the bag,
携帯ゲームもカバンに詰めて、
and let's destroy everything we don't need.
いらないものは全部、壊していこう
That photo, that diary too,
あの写真も、あの日録も、
we don't need any of that anymore.
今となってもういらないさ
This is the journey of a murderer
人殺しと、ダメ人間の君と僕の旅だ。
and a good-for-nothing, you and me.
そして僕らは怯え出したこの狭い狭いこの世界から
And so we fled in terror from this narrow, narrow world,
家族もクラスの奴らも何もかも全部捨てて君と二人で
abandoning families, classmates, and everything else to be alone together,
遠い遠い誰もいない場所で二人で死ぬのよ
to die together in some distant place where no one else is.
もうこの世界に価値などないよ人殺しなんてそこら中充満してるじゃんか
This world has no value left; murderers are overflowing everywhere anyway.
君は何も悪くないよ君は何も悪くないよ
You didn't do anything wrong, you didn't do anything wrong.
結局僕ら誰にも愛されたことなどなかったんだ
After all, neither of us was ever loved by anyone.
そんな嫌な共通点で僕らは簡単に信じ合ってきた
Over that hateful common ground, we so easily trusted each other.
君の手を握った時微かな震えも既になくなっていて
When I held your hand, the faint trembling was already gone,
誰にも縛られないで二人線路の上を歩いた
and unbound by anyone, the two of us walked along the tracks.
金を盗んで二人で逃げてどこにも行ける気がしたんだ
Stealing money and fleeing together, it felt like we could go anywhere.
今更怖いものなんて僕らにはなかったんだ
There was nothing left for us to be afraid of anymore.
額の汗も落ちた眼鏡も「今となってはどうでもいいさ
Sweat on our brows, fallen glasses—'It doesn't matter now anyway,
あぶれ者の小さな逃避行の旅だ」
a small fugitive journey of outcasts.'
いつか夢見た優しくて誰にも好かれる主人公なら
If we were protagonists dreamed of one day, kind and loved by everyone,
汚くなってしまった僕たちも見捨てずにちゃんと救ってくれるのかな？
would someone save us filthied ones properly without abandoning us?
「そんな夢なんて捨ててたよだって現実をみろよ？
“I threw away such dreams, because look at reality!
幸せの四文字なんてなかった今までの人生で思い知ったじゃないか
Didn't our lives so far teach us there's no four-letter word for happiness?
自分は何も悪ねえと誰かがきっと持ってる
Someone surely possesses the excuse that they did nothing wrong,
当て所もなくさような夏の世界に水もなくなって揺れ出す視界に
aimlessly wandering into that summer world, with water gone and vision shaking,
迫り狂う鬼たちの怒号に馬鹿みたいにはしゃぎ合って
frolicking like fools amidst the roaring cries of raging demons,
ふと君はナイフを取った。
you suddenly picked up a knife.
「君が今まで側にいたからここまでこれたんだ。
“I made it this far because you were by my side until now.
だからもういいよ。もういいよ。死ぬのは私一人でいいよ」
So it's okay now. It's okay. I can die all by myself.”
そして君は首を切った。
And then you slashed your throat.
まるで何かの映画のワンシーンだ。
It was just like a scene from some movie.
白昼夢を見ている気がした。
I felt like I was having a daydream.
気づけば僕は捕まって。
Before I knew it, I was caught.
君がどこにも見つからなくて。
And you couldn't be found anywhere.
君だけがどこにもいなくって。
Only you were nowhere to be found.
そして時は過ぎていった。
And time went on passing.
ただ暑い暑い日が過ぎていった。
Just hot, sweltering days kept passing by.
家族もクラスの奴らもいるのになぜか君だけはどこにもいない。
Even though my family and classmates are around, somehow only you are nowhere to be found.
あの夏の日の思い出をぼくは今でも今でも歌っている。
I am still singing the memories of that summer day, even now.
君をずっと探しているんだ。
I've been searching for you all this time.
君に言いたいことがあるんだ。
There's something I want to tell you.
九月の終わりにくしゃみをして六月の匂いを繰り返す。
Sneezing at the end of September, repeating the scent of June.
君の笑顔は、君の無邪気さは、頭の中を飽和している。
Your smile, your innocence—they saturate my mind.
誰も何も悪くないよ。君は何も悪くないから、
No one is at fault. Because you did nothing wrong,
もういいよ、投げ出してしまおう。
it's okay, let's just throw it all away.
そう言って欲しかったのだろうな？なあ？
Is that what you wanted me to say? Huh?
そして君は首を切った。
And then you slashed your throat.
まるで何かの映画のワンシーンだ。
It was just like a scene from some movie.
白昼夢を見ている気がした。
I felt like I was having a daydream.
気づけば僕は捕まって。
Before I knew it, I was caught.
君がどこにも見つからなくて。君だけがどこにもいなくって。
You couldn't be found anywhere, and only you were nowhere to be found.
そして時は過ぎていった。ただ暑い暑い日が過ぎていった。
And time passed by. Just hot, sweltering days kept passing.
家族もクラスの奴らもいるのになぜか君だけはどこにもいない。
Even though my family and classmates are around, only you are nowhere.
あの夏の日の思い出をぼくは今でも今でも歌っている。
I am still singing the memories of that summer day, even now.
君をずっと探しているんだ。君に言いたいことがあるんだ。
I've been searching for you. There's something I want to tell you.
九月の終わりにくしゃみをして六月の匂いを繰り返す。
Sneezing at the end of September, repeating the scent of June.
君の笑顔は、君の無邪気さは、頭の中を飽和している。
Your smile, your innocence—they saturate my mind.
誰も何も悪くないよ。君は何も悪くないから、
No one is at fault. Because you did nothing wrong,
もういいよ、投げ出してしまおう。そう言って欲しかったのだろうな？
it's okay, let's just throw it all away. Is that what you wanted me to say?
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
Piercing through, I grew closer to a hero
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
If you close your eyes and touch it,
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
An evil with the same shape and warmth
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why is it wrong for me, but okay for them?
そこに壁が あっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there,
生まれてしまった 運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate of being born
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free!
鳥のように 羽根があれば
If we had wings like birds,
どこへだって行けるけれど
We could go anywhere we wanted,
帰る場所が なければきっと
But if there's no place to return to,
どこへも行けない
Surely we can't go anywhere at all.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just living on like this.
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛するよ
This world is cruel, but even so, I love you.
なにかを犠牲にしてでも それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is believing strongly in yourself.
鉄の雨が 降り散る情景
The scene of iron rain falling scattering
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
Looked like a movie on TV
戦争なんて 愚かな凶行
War is such foolish brutality
関係ない 知らない国の話
A story of a country I don't know
それならなんで あいつに憎んで
So why do I resent them?
黒い気持ち 隠しきれない理由
The reason I can't hide my dark feelings
説明だって できやしないんだ
I can't even explain it
鉄の雨が 降り続く情景
The scene of iron rain continuing to fall
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
Looked like a movie on TV
戦争なんて 愚かな凶行
War is such foolish brutality
関係ない 知らない国の話
A story of a country I don't know
それならなんで あいつに憎んで
So why do I resent them?
黒い気持ち 隠しきれない理由
The reason I can't hide my dark feelings
説明だって できやしないんだ
I can't even explain it
僕らはなんて 矛盾ばっかりなんだ
We are such contradictions!
この言葉も 歪められたって
Even if these words are distorted,
本当の意味は 伝わらない
Their true meaning won't be conveyed.
信じるのは その目を開いて
Believing is opening your eyes
触れたくて 確かめたいだけ
Wanting to touch and confirm
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just living on like this.
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛するよ
This world is cruel, but even so, I love you.
なにかを犠牲にしてでも それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you.
選んだ人の影 捨てたもののしかばね
The shadow of the chosen, the corpse of what was thrown away
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized, growing inside me is an evil child.
正義の裏 犠牲の中心には 悪魔の子
Behind righteousness, at the center of sacrifice, is an evil child.
教えて教えてよ その仕組みを
Tell me, tell me how that mechanism works
僕の中に 誰がいるの?
Who is inside of me?
壊れた 壊れたよ この世界で
Broken, I'm broken in this world
君が笑う 何も見えずに
Where you're smiling, seeing nothing.
壊れた僕なんてさ 息を止めて
A broken me, holding my breath...
ほどけない もうほどけないよ 真実さえ freeze
Unraveling, I can no longer unravel, even truth is frozen.
壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない
Breaking, unbreakable, going mad, can't go mad...
壊れた 僕なんてさ 息を止めて
I'm broken anyway, so I halt my breath,
ほどけない もう ほどけないよ 真実さえ
unraveling no more, truth itself in a freeze.
freeze 壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない あなたを見つけて
Freeze... I can break it, unbreakable, I found you...
揺れて歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は透き通って見えなくなって
In this twisted world, I gradually became transparent and invisible.
見つけないで ぼくのことを 見つめないで
Please don't find me, don't look at who I am.
誰もが描いた世界の中で あなたを傷つけたくはないよ
In a world someone drew, I don't want to hurt you.
覚えていて 僕のことを 鮮やかなまま
Remember me, as vivid as I used to be.
無限に広がる孤独が絡まる
Endlessly expanding solitude wraps around me.
無邪気に笑った記憶が刺さって 動けない 動けない 動けないよ
Innocent memories pierce me, and I can't move anymore.
unravelling the world
Unraveling the world
変わってしまった 変えられなかった 2つが絡まる 2人が滅びる
Something changed, unchangeable, two intertwine, two perish.
壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない あなたを汚さないよ
I can break it, unbreakable, I won't let you be defiled!
揺れて歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は透き通って見えなくなって
In this twisted world, I grow transparent and invisible.
見つけないで 僕のことを 見つめないで
Please don't find me, don't look upon me.
誰かが仕組んだ孤独な罠に 未来がほぐれてしまう前に
Before the future unravels in this lonely trap someone made,
思い出して 僕のことを 鮮やかなまま
Please remember me, as vivid as I used to be.
忘れないで 忘れないで 忘れないで 忘れないで
Don't forget, don't forget, don't forget, don't forget...
変わってしまったことに paralyze 変えられないことだらけの paradise 覚えていて 僕のことを
Paralyzed by change, in a paradise of unchangeables, remember me.
教えて 教えて 僕の中に誰がいるの？
Tell me, tell me... who lies within me?
誰が袖に咲く幻花 ただそこに藍を落とした
Phantom flowers blooming on sleeves, just dropping indigo there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に 銀朱の月を添えて
In a night where colors brightly melt, with a vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って 躓くごとに強くなった
Cutting through the wind, growing stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部 抱きしめて 選ばれなければ 選べばいい
Embracing light, pain, and anger. If unchosen, choose your path.
声を途絶えさせ夜のその向こうへ 涙で滲んでいた
Let your voice echo beyond the night, blurred by tears.
あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡れ
Reverberating all the way to such distant scenery.
何を奏でて誰に届けたくて 不確かままでいい
What to play, who to deliver to, uncertainty is fine.
どんなに暗い感情も どんなに長い葛藤も
No matter how dark the emotions or long the conflict,
歌と成れ残響
become a song and ring on.
誰がために愛を鳴らす
For whose sake does love ring out?
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Who's sleeve does the phantom flower bloom on?
ただ そこに藍を落とした
I just dropped blue there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に 銀朱の月を添えて
In the night where colors melt, with a vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って 躓く毎に強くなった
Cutting through the wind like rolling, stronger with each stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部 抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger.
選ばれなければ 選びゃいい
If you're not chosen, just choose.
声よ轟け 夜のその向こうへ 涙で滲んだ
Shout out, echo beyond the night, tears shimmered.
あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡って
Reverberating to such distant views.
何を奏でて 誰に届けたくて 不確かなままでいい
What to play, who to deliver to, it's fine to remain uncertain.
どんなに暗い感情も どんなに長い葛藤も 歌と成れ残響
No matter how dark emotions or long battles, become a song, reverberation.
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you're not chosen, just choose.
声をからして 燃える花のように
Like a burning flower with a strained voice,
闇間を照らしたら
when you light up the darkness.
曖昧過ぎる正解も宛名にして 夜を数えて朝を描くような
Letting vague answers be forgiven, counting nights to paint mornings,
鮮やかな音を鳴らす どんなに深い後悔も どんなに高い限界も
sounding vivid tunes, no matter how deep the regret or high the limit,
掻き消して 残響
scratching it out, reverberation.
ねえ、見て！
Hey, look!
ほら、早く。
Come on, hurry up.
もうやめてよ！
Stop it already!
ん、おいしい！食べてみて！
Mmm, delicious! Try some!
もう、終わりにしない？
Hey, shouldn't we end this?
あなたのことが、ずっと、好きでした。
I've always loved you.
作文の空白を埋めるみたいに 一日をただ過ごした
Like filling in the blanks of an essay, I just spent another day by.
僕はまた狭い部屋で 膝抱き寄せて 笑えるほど何度も何度もでも
Once again in my cramped room, pulling my knees close, laughing over and over.
あなたを巡った 笑顔も声も愛嬌も癖だって
I searched for you—your smile, voice, charm, and habits.
見ているだけでいい そう思っていたのに
Thinking just watching was enough...
愛してくれ 僕のことを どうか邪魔などしないから
Please love me, please don't get in my way.
消せない写真と目合わせて 笑ってくれ 僕のことを
Meeting the eyes of an unforgettable photo, please laugh with me.
あなたには届かないけど 酷く焦がれる恋をしてた
Even though it won't reach you, I was in a desperately burning love.
混ざることない指 息を止める
Fingers that will never entwine, holding my breath.
名も無い僕は 客席の中
A nameless me, sitting in the audience,
舞台の二人 ただ見つめて
just gazing at the two on stage.
今 知らないあなたがまた増える
Now, strangers of you keep increasing—
僕もなんて 肥大した心が醜く溢れた
me, of all people, with my bloated, ugly heart.
目配せの意味 揃いの仕草だって 額縁の中さ
The meaning of a glance, matching gestures, inside the picture frame.
無残に手を伸ばして
Reaching out pathetically,
気付いてくれ 僕の声に 「片思いみたい」だなんて
notice my voice, saying something like "It's unrequited love."
そんな綺麗なものじゃないや
It's not anything that beautiful.
届きやしない歌 独り踊る
I dance alone a song that won't reach you.
たとえばそう あなたがそう
If, for instance, you
僕のことを知らなくても
would never know who I am,
ずっと好きでいててもいいですか
would it be okay if I kept loving you?
でもあなたがいらないなら
But if you don't want me,
この想いがいらないなら
if you don't need these feelings,
いきをとめてしまいたい
I want to stop breathing.
愛してくれ 僕のことも
Love me too, for who I am,
どうか邪魔などしないから
I promise I won't get in your way.
遠い遠い別世界まで
To a far, far away another world,
袖触れないまに 幕が上がる
the curtain rises without our sleeves ever brushing.
ただまた会いたくて
Just because I wanted to see you again,
あなたにこの拍手を
I give this applause to you.
はい！ということで、やっとみんなにね、お届けすることができました！
Yes! So, we were finally able to deliver this to everyone!
一昨年のあの特報、みんな覚えているでしょうか？
Does everyone remember that breaking news from two years ago?
あのですね、あの、『カイカイキータン』や『ドラムソード』などの変曲をなさっている、ぬゆりさんというね、お方に変曲をしていただいて…
Um, Nuyuri-san, who arranged songs like 'Kaikaikitan' and 'Drum Sword', arranged this for me...
あまねがねた作詞・作曲の、えーオリジナル曲『別世界』今回ね、初披露できました！みんなありがとう！
My original song 'Bessekai', with lyrics and composition by me, was premiered this time! Thank you everyone!
ということでですね、そしてたくさんのね、楽曲を歌って、そしてそして、なんといってもこれでねみんな、新衣装です！
So, after singing lots of songs, and above all, with this, everyone, it's a new outfit!
こちらですね、100万人記念で、あの、運営さんに作っていただきました。ありがとうございます！どう？ちょっと歌うときに着る衣装っていうことで、お揃い風に仕立てていただきました！
Here, management made this for me for reaching 1 million subscribers. Thank you! How is it? As an outfit to wear when singing, they tailored it to match with you!
ということでですね、えーみんな、もう1曲、やっぱりあの曲歌っとかないとっていうのが、あるよねということで、あの曲を歌いたいと思います。
So, everyone, there's another song, of course we have to sing that song, right? So I'd like to sing that song.
そしてそのあとにはですね、あのグッズの紹介もございますので、あっ、そうそうそう、そういえば！
And after that, we also have merchandise introductions, oh right, come to think of it!
今日はもう1回、最後におきがえを用意しているんでした、ということで、あの、ちょっとおきがえしたいと思います。そしてステージもですね、ちょっとあの、こっちに移動したいと思いますので、それじゃ行くか！
Today we have one more costume change prepared for the end, so I'd like to go change clothes. And the stage will also move over here, so well, let's go!
みんなもね、おそろいの服持ってるはずだから、きとけよっていうことでじゃあ、みんな移動するよー！
Everyone should have the matching clothes too, so put them on! Alright, everyone, we're moving!
特者生存ワンラダー!! 作詞・作曲：田淵智也
[Song: Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der!! / Lyrics & Comp: Tomoya Tabuchi]
なぬっ!? ビシッ おりゃっ パシッ
Nanu!? Bishi! Oorya! Pashic!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
Sharp retorts, perfect weather today.
さわっ… ぎゅむっ バキッ 手にする全部 It's mine!
Sawawall... Gyumu! Baki! Everything in my hands, It's mine!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか?)
Trying hard in moderation (Is that so?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
Well, even that's fine, I guess.
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ!)
Trying my absolute best (That's right!)
それが僕らしいよな
That's just more like me, isn't it?
ダサすぎんじゃねえだろっ そんで貧乏性じゃねえだろっ
It's not like I'm too tacky or a miser!
うん! 万事がバッチリイケてるに決まってる!
Yeah! Everything's in place, bound to be going great!
どどん! 前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して 高まれ
Dodon! Advance is approved! Welcome properly, get hyped!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して 興奮しよう
Sea and sky creation, be amazed properly, let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん 現実 超えろ未来 あー!
Because I'm the one saying it, I'm really gonna do it! Reality, transcend the future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチー!
Weaknesses are fine too, launcher with a switch!
すなわち 特者生存ワンラダーday 楽しもう
In other words, Survivor Wonder-la-der Day, let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し 堪えおらん、over? 返事聞かせてくれ!
Search for things to find amusing, over? Let me hear your reply!
右左 なんかじゃない (かなたーん!)
Not left or right (Kanata-n!)
決まりつけて一直線 (かなたーん!)
Decided straight ahead (Kanata-n!)
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ ワクワク進んでシャ!
In other words, once you plot it, launch is all right, so exciting! Sha!
みんな！、『別世界』のMVはこのあとすぐに、かなたチャンネルで投稿予定でございます！ぜひぜひたくさん聞いていっぱいっぱい歌ってください！
Everyone! The MV for 'Bessekai' will be posted right after this on Kanata's channel! Please listen to it a lot and sing it loads!
なんだよそんなこ…
What is it, things like that...
いけーっ！はい！はい！なぬっ！？ビシッおりゃっ！パシッ
Let's go! Yes! Yes! What?! Bam! Take that! Slap!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
Even my comebacks are sharp, today is clear skies!
さぁっ ボロ… ぎゅっ バキッ
Come on, tattered... squeeze, snap!
手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれ
Everything in my hands, it's mine! Give it here!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか？)
Let's work hard in moderation (Is that so?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine too, but
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ！)
Let's try our hardest (That's right!)
それが僕ららしいよな
That's just like us, isn't it?
ダサすぎじゃねんだわ！
It's not uncool at all!
貧乏っちいじゃねんだわ！
It's not pathetic at all!
うん！ 万事がバッチリ イケてるに決まってる！
Yeah! Everything's going perfectly!
(are you?) かなたんっ
(Are you?) Kanatan!
どうん！ 前進上等！ ちゃんと歓迎して
Boom! Full speed ahead! Welcome it properly,
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
create sea and sky, be amazed properly,
興奮しようぜ ぼくが言うんだもん
let's get excited, since I'm saying so!
本当にするんだもん 現実を超えろ未来
I'll really make it happen, surpass reality, future!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch!
すなわち 特者生存 ワンダラダday 楽しもうぜ
In other words, survival of the fittest wonder-la-der day!
面白がれること 探しほうだいだぜ
Let's have fun, searching for things to enjoy
無限のフィールドで
in an endless field!
パンキングしなくてもいい ど真ん中一直線
No need to panic, straight down the middle!
つまり これが僕の答えなんだ
In other words, this is my answer.
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Puff out your chest, for the meaning of living now!
明くる日も 明くる来る日も 確かめ進め！
Day after day, and the days after that, push forward!
おうりゃー！
Oh yeah!
聞いて！！
Listen!!
推しイベきちゃあああ アイドルオタク楽しい～！
My favorite's event is here! Idol otaku life is so fun~!
デモ
But...
ガチ恋の結婚は立ち直れていません
I still haven't recovered from my oshi's marriage.
ガチャだ！！ 出るまで回せば 100% ピックアップ！！
It's gacha!! Spin until you get it for 100% pick-up!!
ｗｗｗｗ 天井でーす ｗｗｗｗ
Lolol, that's hitting pity! Lolol
何だよ そんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おばか！
What's with that, you mustn't say things like that, dummy!
うわ～すごい！ ありがちょ～
Wow~ amazing! Thanks a bunch~
日々これ挑戦で go my way!
Day in and day out, challenge it, go my way!
虎視眈々 でいたいんだもん
Keep a watchful eye, that's how I want to be!
だって意気 ガンガン が いいんだもん
Because a blazing fighting spirit is what I want!
全方位 に がっちり アンテナ 張ってなくちゃ！
Gotta keep our antennas firmly tuned in all directions!
いつでも 心 は ちゃんと 純真 でいたいな
Always want my heart to remain truly pure.
好奇心 は 絶えず 熱心 でいたいな って
Always want my curiosity to burn with passion.
言い聞かせる ん だ 調子 に 乗っ たら
Reminding myself, because if I get carried away,
すぐ 飽き られ ちゃう から あー！
I'll get bored of it right away, ah!
タイト な ロープ も どんと来い でっせ
Even a tightrope, bring it on!
すなわち 特者生存 ワンダラダday しがみつけ
In other words, survival of the fittest wonder-la-der day, hold on!
努力 とは 最後 まで 諦め ない こと メモっておいて！
"Effort is never giving up until the end" - make a note of it!
ホント は baby 自信 なんか ないよ
The truth is, baby, I don't have any confidence.
ホント は baby 不安 ばっか で 泣き そう だ
The truth is, baby, I'm so full of anxiety I could cry.
でもね baby 挫け ないって 決めた の
But you know, baby, I decided I wouldn't break down.
だから baby 挑戦 したいよ 未開 の 天地
That's why, baby, I want to challenge uncharted lands,
無限 の フィールド で ギター！
in an infinite field! Guitar!
前進上等！ ちゃんと歓迎して
Full speed ahead! Welcome it properly,
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
create sea and sky, be amazed properly,
ボク が 言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
since I'm saying so, I'll really make it happen!
現実 超えろ 未来 あー！
Surpass reality, future, ah!
弱点 も 平気 スイッチ で ランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch!
すなわち 特者生存 ワンダラダday 楽しもう
In other words, survival of the fittest wonder-la-der day!
面白 がれる こと 探し 放題 でっせ
Searching freely for things we can enjoy,
無限 の フィールド で
in an infinite field!
パンキング し なく ても いい
No need to panic,
ど真ん中 一直線
straight down the middle!
つまり これが ボク の 答え なんだ
In other words, this is my answer.
胸 を 張れ 今 を 生きる その 意味 を
Puff out your chest, for the meaning of living now!
明くる日 も 明くる来る日 も 確かめ 進め！
Day after day, and the days after that, push forward!
どうん！ 前進上等！
Boom! Full speed ahead!
すなわち 特者生存 ワンダラダday
In other words, survival of the fittest wonder-la-der day!
楽しもうぜ 面白がれること
Let's have fun, finding things to enjoy,
探し放題でっせ 無限のフィールドで
searching freely in an infinite field!
パンキングしなくてもいい ど真ん中一直線
No need to panic, straight down the middle!
つまりこれがボクの答えなんだ
In other words, this is my answer.
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Puff out your chest, for the meaning of living now!
明くる日も 明くる来る日も 確かめ進め！
Day after day, and the days after that, push forward!
オーリャー！
Oh yeah!
がんばれ がんばれ！
Do your best, do your best!
つまりこれがボクの答えなんだ
In other words, this is my answer.
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Puff out your chest, for the meaning of living now!
明くる日も 明くる来る日も 確かめ進め！
Day after day, and the days after that, push forward!
オーリャー！
Oh yeah!
かなたんすっき！
I love Kanatan!
3周年記念ライブ、楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
I hope you all enjoyed the 3rd Anniversary Live!
今回もグッズが登場いたします。
Merchandise will also be available this time.
グッズは4種類ございまして、アクリルスタンド、タンブラー、お守り、ラバーコースターとなっております。
There are 4 items: acrylic stand, tumbler, amulet, and rubber coaster.
そして今回もグッズのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には、購入特典のポストカードと特典ボイスがついてきます。
Also, those who purchase the full set will receive a bonus postcard and voice clips.
今回も直筆サイン数量限定なんですが、書かせていただきますのでよろしくお願いいたします。
There are limited quantities with handwritten signatures, so please check them out!
アクリルスタンドはうなぽっぷ先生に描いていただきました！
The acrylic stand was illustrated by Una-pop-sensei!
とっても素敵なイラストとなっております。ぜひぜひデスクなどに置いてください！いつでもかなたと一緒です。
It's a wonderful illustration. Please display it on your desk! You'll always be with Kanata.
えーそしてお守り。こちら双葉はる先生に描いていただきました。
And next, the amulet, illustrated by Futaba Haru-sensei.
ウパを想い出すこの可愛いお守りどこにつけてもあなたを守るはず。
This cute amulet reminding you of Upa will protect you wherever you attach it.
えーそしてタンブラー。こちらですね、とっても大人っぽいデザインにしていただいたので、職場でも学校でも使えると思われます。
And the tumbler. It has a very mature design, so you can use it at work or school.
そしてこのパッケージめっちゃかっけえです。
And the packaging looks super cool.
そしてタンブラーの下に敷くのはラバーコースター！これでもどれだけ結露しても大丈夫、デスクは汚しません。
Under the tumbler is a rubber coaster! It prevents any condensation from messing up your desk.
こちら3周年記念のフルセットはなんとなんと、お値段6,000円となっております！
The 3rd Anniversary Full Set is priced at 6,000 yen!
そしてそしてフルセットの購入特典はこちらでございます！数量限定バージョンは直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと特典ボイス。
Here are the purchase bonuses! The limited version includes a signed and foiled postcard and voice clips.
そして普通のフルセットの方は、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと特典ボイスとなっております。
The regular full set includes a foiled signed/message postcard and voice clips.
ということで皆さん、天音かなた活動3周年記念のグッズもよろしくお願いいたします！
With that everyone, please look forward to Kanata's 3rd anniversary merch!
そしてこの後は新曲『別世界』のMVが投稿されます！こちらの絵のぶんマジでめちゃくちゃ動くからよろしくお願いします。プレミア公開このまま飛べるんで絶対見てください！
After this, the MV for the new song 'Bessekai' will premiere! The illustrations move so much, so please check out the premiere right here!
そしてそのあと22時15分からメンバー限定配信でアンコールライブやりますので、そちら気になる方はぜひメンバー入って一緒にライブの余韻楽しもうよ！ということで今回もありがとうございました！天音かなたでした！
And then at 22:15 we'll have a member-only encore live stream! If you're interested, join membership and let's enjoy the afterglow together! Thank you as always, this was Amane Kanata!